Roy Crane Papers
Roy Crane Papers
- Correspondence
  - Outgoing correspondence
    - Wallace Willis letter, 14 Oct 1973 (Box 4)
  - Clark Haas correspondence
    - [General], 1953-1961; undated; extensive correspondence between Crane and his assistant Clark Haas (and others?); includes letters, scenarios, sketches, proofs and tear sheets; 2 folders (Box 5)
- Drawings and sketches
  - Boats and seascapes sketches, undated (Oversize 15)
  - Buz Sawyer, Rosco Sweeney sketches and roughs, undated (Oversize 15)
  - Cartoon fragments, undated; miscellaneous unidentified fragments detached from original Wash Tubbs/Captain Easy, Buz Sawyer, and Roscoe Sweeney cartoons (Oversize 57)
  - Characters/faces, undated (Oversize 15)
  - Christmas cards, undated; sketches and printed cards; 4 items (Oversize 15)
  - Early work, 1918-1924; early sketches and original drawings for magazine illustrations (Oversize 16)
  - Fights, undated (Oversize 16)
  - Frank Battle sketches, 1930; includes handwritten note from Crane, "sketches for Jack Battle [sic], a Sunday page that never came out because the Depression hit just two months before. The page had a pre-Revolutionary War background."; approximately 25 items (Oversize 16)
  - Juvenilia, 1908-1918; 4 (Oversize 16)
  - Landscapes/backgrounds, undated (Oversize 17)
  - Miscellaneous roughs and sketches, undated; motion studies, animals, etc. (Oversize 17)
  - Trains, 1930-1935; 6 items (Oversize 17)
  - Travel sketches, undated; people and locations in Mexico and various sites in the United States (Oversize 17)
  - Wash Tubbs and Captain Easy sketches, 3 items (Oversize 17)
  - Whaling sketches, circa 1935 (Oversize 17)
  - Women, undated (Oversize 17)
- Promotional material
  - Music to the Ear
    - Promotional poster, early 1920s; includes handwritten note from Crane on back of one poster: "This was my first try on a syndicated feature..."; 6 copies (Oversize 13)
  - South of Rio Grande
    - Promotional poster, [1927]; 2 copies (Oversize 13)
      "Lines and Sketches From an Artist's Notebook" by Roy Crane
  - Wash Tubbs/Captain Easy
    - Posters, fliers and ads, 1924-1943; 18 (Oversize 13)
    - Miscellaneous, 1924-1943; fliers, print ads, NEA booklet, "Snap" (NEA in-house magazine) and Wash Tubbs flipbook; 7 items (Box 6)
    - Miscellaneous, circa 1924; announcements, promo articles, posters, sample strips, and bio clips on Crane; approximately 12 items (Volume 1)
    - Miscellaneous, circa 1924; promo articles and news clips on Crane and Wash Tubbs; approximately 6 items (Volume 2)
    - Miscellaneous, circa 1924; announcements, promo articles, posters, sample strips, copies of "Snap" (NEA in-house magazine), and bio clips on Crane; approximately 25 items (Volume 20)
  - Buz Sawyer
    - Letters/packets to subscribing papers, 1962-1972; letter and 2 column mat issued by King Features; "The following copy and the accompanying mat are for your use in promoting the new continuity that starts..."; 29 items (Box 6)
    - Posters, fliers and ads, 10 items (Oversize 13)
    - Syndicate sales presentation booklet, 1954 (Oversize 13)
    - Miscellaneous promotional materials, syndicate announcements, fliers, booklets, sample proofs and ads; 15 items (Box 6)
- Published material
  - Articles and clippings about Crane and his work, 1927-1965; undated; xerox copies, newspaper and magazine clippings; 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Comic books
    - Buz Sawyer, Standard (No. 2), 1948 (Box 7)
    - Buz Sawyer Featuring His Pal Rosco Sweeney, missing cover (Box 7)
    - Captain Easy, Dell Four-Color Comics Series 2 (No. 111), 1946 (Box 7)
  - Early illustration work
    - Coming Events Cast Their Shadows, 1919; tear sheet for panel cartoon from Fort Worth Record (Box 7)
    - How To Make Money, undated; magazine cover (Box 7)
    - I Confess magazine, 1923; tear sheets for story illustrations (Box 7)
    - I Didn't Know You'd Be Sorry sheet music, 1927 (Box 7)
    - Judge magazine, 22 Sep 1923; Crane illustration on page 21 (Box 7)
    - Our National Pastime, 1922; tear sheet of panel cartoon from The Longhorn Magazine (Box 7)
    - The Wayne Whispers, undated; magazine cover (Box 7)
    - Miscellaneous, early 1920s; xerox copies of Crane's early illustration work, including examples of his cartoons published in The Longhorn Magazine during Crane's college days; 43 pages (Box 7)
  - Navy publications, 1954-1964; pamphlets, CHINFO newsletters, memo; 7 items (Box 7)
  - Newspaperboys' Hall of Fame, 1955; letter and pamphlet; 2 items (Box 7)
  - Pamphlets by others, 1949-1962; 3 items (Box 7)
- Research material
  - For Buz Sawyer
    - Notebooks, pocket notebooks containing story ideas, research notes and travel notes from trips to Cuba, Viet Nam, the Philippines and elsewhere; 16 items (Box 8)
    - Research notes and pamphlets, notes on Naval aircraft, military practices, drug smuggling; pamphlets, fliers and forms related to Cuban immigration (Box 8)
    - Research clippings and articles, newspaper and magazine clippings related to defense technology, submarines, military slang and miscellaneous other topics (Box 8)
  - For Wash Tubbs
    - Circus research, 1925-1927; letters, notes, sketches, photographs; 50 items (Box 8)
- Writings
  - Comic strips scripts and scenarios
    - Buz Sawyer, typed and handwritten scripts/scenarios for story continuities
      - Scripts/scenarios, alphabetical by title, 4 folders (Box 8)
      - Notebooks 1-14, legal pads with loose pages interspersed (most 8 ½ x 14 in.); sketches, handwritten story notes and drafts, and some loose typed pages; 14 items (Box 9)
      - Notebooks 15-27, legal pads with loose pages interspersed (most 8 ½ x 14 in.); sketches, handwritten story notes and drafts, and some loose typed pages; 13 items (Box 10)
    - Other comic strips
      - Family Strip, typed proposal for comic strip; handwritten note from Crane: "perhaps I was considering doing a second strip, in addition to Buz"; 4 pages (Box 8)
      - Fortune Street, typed proposal for comic strip; handwritten note from Crane: "considered as a strip when switching to King Features"; 3 pages (Box 8)
      - Mickey Ireland, typed proposal for comic strip, an early version of Buz Sawyer; 2 pages (Box 8)
    - Rosco Sweeney
      - Stories by Crane, typed and handwritten scripts/scenarios for story continuities (Box 8)
      - Story by Jack Mendelsohn, story board, sketches, typed script and proofs (Box 8)
    - Wash Tubbs/Captain Easy
      - Scripts/scenarios, alphabetical by title, typed and handwritten scripts/scenarios for story continuities; 22 stories (Box 8)
  - Camels in Texas, by Roy Crane [story], undated; 9 page typescript; 9 pages (Box 11)
  - The First Few Knocks Are the Hardest, by Roy Crane [article], undated; 2 page typescript; 2 pages (Box 11)
  - The Marines Tell It To Crane, author unknown [article], undated; 5 page typescript; 5 pages (Box 11)
  - Roy Crane Interview [radio script], undated; 7 page typed/handwritten radio script for Crane interview on WORZ radio; 7 pages (Box 11)
  - Miscellaneous speeches, drafts and research notes by Crane for speeches, including material on the history and importance of comics, the social role of comics and the instructional use of comics; approximately 25 items (Box 11)